翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So let's just work through each of the memory boxes,
让我们检查每个内存盒子
and we'll start with size.
从 size 开始
Should size be decreased?
size 应该缩小吗？
Well, our intuition says, of course, yes, it should go down to 5.
直觉告诉我们，应该降到5
But we can also see that in our invariants, that also rings true.
我们可以看到，这在不变量中也是对的
So by changing from 6 to 5, we have, for example, that the position of the next item to be inserted is always going to be size.
通过将6改为5，我们可以确定下一项要插入的位置将始终是 size
It'll be here now instead, so that if somebody does removeLast
它此时在这里，如果有人调用 removeLast
and then add last 20, that 20 will appear here.
再添加20，20就会出现在这里
We also need it so that size is always the number of items in the a list,
我们还需要知道 size 始终是链表中的项数
and the last item in the list should always be in position size minus 1.
链表中的最后一项应该始终处于 size-1 位置
In other words, if we removeLast and change from-- size from 6 to 5,
换句话说，如果我们调用 removeLast 并将6改为5
we'll see that the last item on the list is indeed in position 4, which is 5 minus 1, or 4. OK?
我们会看到链表的最后一项确实在位置4，也就是5-1
How about items?
items 呢？
Should items change?
items 是否应该更改？
Well, if items change, then we're basically saying,
如果 items 改变，那么基本上...
I need to change these 64 bits so that this now points at a new totally different array.
我需要更改这64位，以使它指向一个完全不同的新数组
There is no reason for that.
这是没有道理的
Why would we need another array?
为什么需要另一个数组？
Lastly, how about items I?
最后，items[i] 呢？
That is, do we need actually change this?
我们真的需要改变这个吗？
Do we need to change this minus 1 to be, say, 0 or whatever?
我们需要把这个-1改成0吗？
And if we look at our invariants,
看看我们的不变量
we see, actually, no.
没有
We don't really need to do that.
我们真的不需要这么做
As far as our invariants are concerned,
就我们的不变量而言
we can just leave this minus 1 around.
我们可以把这个-1放在一边
And I think the analogy is basically if someone does finger shoot this bird,
这样类比，如果有人射杀了这只鸟
it's OK to lower this bird, and you don't actually have to destroy it.
把这只鸟放下来就行了，并不需要摧毁它
So that's all we need to change is size in order for things to work.
所以只需改变 size，一切正常工作
Let's try it out.
让我们试试看
So now, let's be the puppet masters of reality,
让我们成为现实的木偶大师
and we'll do so as follows.
我们将这样做
So when you removeLast, we need to delete the item and also return it.
执行 removeLast 时，需要删除该项并将其返回
So I'll start by just setting aside the last item.
所以我先把最后一项放在一边
All right, and I get the last item
获取最后一项
so that I can give it back out to the world later.
这样我就可以把它返回给世界了
And later, I'm going to return x.
稍后我将返回x
But before I do that, I actually need to destroy the item.
但在这么做之前，我需要销毁这项
Now, as we just said,
就像刚才说的
the only way that we need to manipulate to destroy the item--  the little figure so that the outside world sees the shadows on the wall it expects--
我们唯一需要操纵的就是摧毁这个小图案，以便外界看到期望的墙壁上的阴影
is to simply say size equals size minus 1.
简单地说，size = size - 1
Could we also actually do something like items size equals zero?
还需要 items[size] = 0 吗？
Yeah, won't hurt, but unnecessary.
可以，但没必要
So we can save ourselves some effort
我们可以省些力气
by not destroying the bird once we lower it from in front of the fire.
把鸟从火炉前放下来就行了，不必毁了它
So this is the simplest possible removeLast method,
这是最简单的 removeLast 方法
but there are other ways you could do it.
还有其他方法
So on this slide, I have an alternate version of removeLast,
这张幻灯片上有一个备用版本的 removeLast
where, in this case,
在这种情况下
we actually think more about the bits--
我们实际上更多考虑的是位...
or think more about the concrete reality
更多地考虑到具体的现实
by-- instead of using getLast, here I've said,
而不是使用 getLast
equals item size minus 1.
等于 items[size-1]
So either approach is fine, though I find this approach slightly nicer.
这两种方法都很好，不过我觉得这种方法稍微好一点
It just reads better.
更易读
It's more narrative, but up to you.
它叙述性更强，但由你决定
This line right here is wholly unnecessary,
这行完全没有必要
but maybe it strikes you as something you like.
但也许你喜欢
We definitely need to do size minus 1,
size 必须减去1
and we need to return this item.
需要返回该项
So both of these are valid approaches,
这两种方法都有效
though I prefer the version I just did live.
虽然我更喜欢刚刚直播的版本
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
But I'm including this as an alternate solution.
但我把这个作为一个替代解决方案